Guide to the Lawrence Langner Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Lawrence Langner papers
1913-1983
1920-1962
YCAL MSS 688
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
47.8
(119 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
The papers include writings, correspondence, subject files, photographs and other materials relating to Lawrence Langner's work as an author, theater producer, and patent attorney. Writings include plays (Suzanna and the Elders and The Pursuit of Happiness, among others); articles on various aspects of theatre and patent law; and books, including his autobiography, The Magic Curtain; The Importance of Wearing Clothes; and G.B.S. and the Lunatic. Correspondence, subject files, and financial records relate to the writing, production, and publication of Langner's writings; his work with the Theatre Guild; his law firm; and the National Inventors Council, among other topics. Typescript iterations of plays including A Moon for the Misbegotten and Strange Interlude by Eugene O'Neill, inscribed by O'Neill to Langner, are also included. Correspondence between Bernard Shaw and Langner relating to the production of Shaw plays by the Theatre Guild; annotated proofs of Back to Methuselah, Geneva, and St. Joan; and a typescript article by Shaw form the final group of material in the papers.
Langner, Lawrence, 1890-1962
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bequest of Lawrence Langner, 1964.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 118: Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Associated Materials
Theatre Guild Archive (YCAL MSS 436). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.
Biographical/Historical note
Lawrence Langner was born in Swansea, South Wales in 1890, and immigrated to the United States in 1903. After settling in New York City, as a young man he studied patent law and was involved in New York theatre, assisting in establishing and writing plays for the Washington Square Players and The Provincetown Players, among others. With a small group of other New York theatre devotees Langner established the Theatre Guild in 1918. Langner spent the remainder of his life as co-director of the Guild with Theresa Helburn, producing stage, radio, and television shows and introducing important playwrights, directors, and actors as well as innovative stage techniques to American audiences. In 1931 Langner and his wife, Armina Marshall, established the Westport Country Playhouse near their home in Connecticut, and he founded the American Shakespeare Festival Theatre and Academy in Stratford, Connecticut, in 1951. In addition to his work in the performing arts, he was a senior partner in the law firm of Langner, Parry, Card and Langner, and was a leader in the field of patent law. A prolific writer of plays, articles, and books, Langner's autobiography, The Magic Curtain: the Story of a Life in Two Fields, Theatre and Invention, was published in 1951. He died in New York in 1962.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes writings, correspondence, subject files, and other materials relating to Lawrence Langner's work as an author, theatre producer, and patent attorney. Writings include plays ( Suzanna and the Elders and The Pursuit of Happiness among others); articles on various aspects of theatre and patent law; and books, including his autobiography, The Magic Curtain, The Importance of Wearing Clothes, and G.B.S. and the Lunatic. Correspondence, subject files, and financial records relate to the writing, production, and publication of Langner's writings; his work with the Theatre Guild; his law firm; and the National Inventors Council, among other topics. Typescript iterations of plays including A Moon for the Misbegotten and Strange Interlude by Eugene O'Neill, inscribed by O'Neill to Langner, are also included. Correspondence between Bernard Shaw and Langner relating to the production of Shaw plays by the Theatre Guild; annotated proofs of Back to Methuselah, Geneva, and St. Joan; and a typescript article by Shaw form the final group of material in the papers.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in four groupings: I. 1964 Acquisition, 1917-1963. II. Material Formerly Part of the Eugene O'Neill Papers, 1913-1963. III. Material Formerly Part of the Theatre Guild Archive, 1914-1983. IV. Material Formerly Classed as MS Vault Shelves Shaw, 1921-1938.
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Patent laws and legislation -- United States; Patent lawyers -- United States; Theater -- Production and direction -- New York (State) -- New York; Theater -- United States; Theatrical producers and directors -- United States; Photographs; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Patent lawyers -- United States -- 20th Century; Theatrical producers and directors -- United States -- 20th Century; Langner, Lawrence, 1890-1962; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950; National Inventors Council (U.S.); Theatre Guild
- 1964 Acquisition, 1917-1963; Series I; 37.95; (95 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized under two headings: Writings and Correspondence and Subject Files.
  - Writings, 1917-1963
    Scope and Contents
    Includes drafts, typescripts, and published editions of playscripts (including adaptations and collaborations), books, and articles. Titles may be accompanied by related correspondence and other material.
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Adler's lectures (notes), 1927 January, undated; 3 (Box 1)
    - "America Dances", 1934-1935, undated; 9 (Box 1)
    - "America Dances", 1934 March-July, undated; 6 (Box 2)
    - Another Way Out, 1951 December 5, undated (Box 2)
      Includes translations in Italian and French
    - "At the Income Tax Office", undated; 7 (Box 2)
    - "The Ballet at Windsor", 1938 (Box 2)
    - "Ballet Play", undated; 3 (Box 2)
    - "Better Faces", undated (Box 3)
    - "The Birth of a Bacchante", undated (Box 3)
    - "The Borderline Girl", 1924, undated; 5 (Box 3)
    - "Brigham Young", 1926 November 19, undated (Box 3)
    - "Celebrities", 1926, undated; 2 (Box 3)
    - "Check Mate!", 1927-1928 (Box 3)
      Variant titles: "The Marriage Business" and "Husband, Inc."
    - "Check Mate!", 1927-1928; 3 (Box 4)
    - "Check Mate!", 1927-1928; 8 (Box 5)
    - "A Christmas Interlude", undated (Box 5)
    - "The Christmas Tree", undated (Box 5)
    - "Cinderella Play", undated (Box 6)
    - "Class IA", undated (Box 6)
    - "Counterpoint", 1929; 2 (Box 6)
    - The Country Wife, 1929-1954; 4 (Box 6)
    - "Cuba Libra", undated; 2 (Box 6)
    - "Cuba Libra", 1933-1949, undated; 9 (Box 7)
    - "Cuban Trip", 1933, undated; 2 (Box 8)
    - "Dance School", undated (Box 8)
    - "The Daughter of Intolerance", undated (Box 8)
    - "The Demi-Wife", 1927, undated; 5 (Box 8)
    - "The Democratic Duke", undated (Box 8)
    - Dr. Knock, 1950, undated; 2 (Box 8)
      Variant title: "An Apple a Day"
    - "The Efficient Lover", 1920 (Box 9)
    - "An Examination of Ethics", 1926 September 21 (Box 9)
    - The Family Exit, 1920, undated; 6 (Box 9)
    - "The Famous Case", undated (Box 9)
    - "Fledermaus", undated (Box 10)
    - For Husbands Only, 1932-1952, undated; 7 (Box 10)
    - For Husbands Only, 1929-1932, undated; 7 (Box 11)
    - For Husbands Only, 1927-1929, undated; 9 (Box 12)
    - For Husbands Only, 1931-1932; 3 (Box 13)
    - "For Love or Money", 1934, undated; 6 (Box 13)
    - "Fruits of Culture", 1958 December 2 (Box 13)
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, 1963, undated; 4 (Box 14)
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, 1930-1956, undated; 8 (Box 15)
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, undated; 3 (Box 16)
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, 1963, undated; 5 (Box 17)
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, undated; 2 (Box 18)
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, undated; 7 (Box 19)
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, undated; 10 (Box 20)
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, 1923-1962, undated; 19 (Box 21)
    - "The Gates of Beyond", undated (Box 22)
    - "Hajji Baba", undated (Box 22)
    - "Headlines", undated (Box 22)
    - "Heads or Tails", 1926 January 23 (Box 22)
    - "Help Yourself", 1951, undated; 4 (Box 22)
      Variant titles: "Those Who Help Themselves" and "Help the Strong"
    - "Help Yourself", 1946-1958, undated; 11 (Box 23)
    - "Help Yourself", undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - Henry, Behave, 1922, undated; 6 (Box 24)
      Variant titles: "A Fine Suburban Lot" and "Like Father - Like Son"
    - Henry, Behave, 1922, undated; 6 (Box 25)
    - "The Hive", undated (Box 25)
    - Holding Helen, 1924-1926, undated; 8 (Box 26)
    - Holding Helen, undated; 2 (Box 27)
    - "L'Homme a la Rose", undated (Box 27)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, 1958, undated; 3 (Box 28)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, 1957-1959, undated; 17 (Box 29)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, [no year] July 22, undated; 8 (Box 30)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 13 (Box 31)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 10 (Box 32)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 7 (Box 33)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 18 (Box 34)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 4 (Box 35)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 2 (Box 36)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 9 (Box 37)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, [1960], undated; 7 (Box 38)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, 1959, undated; 9 (Box 39)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, [1951]-1957, undated; 4 (Box 40)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 4 (Box 41)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 5 (Box 42)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, 1953, undated; 7 (Box 43)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, undated; 4 (Box 44)
    - "It Can Happen", undated (Box 44)
    - "Jerusalem Project", 1961-1962; 3 (Box 44)
    - "Jerusalem Project", 1948-1960, undated; 9 (Box 45)
    - "Jewish Play", undated (Box 45)
    - The Keyhole, 1934 November 9, undated; 3 (Box 45)
    - The Keyhole, undated; 4 (Box 46)
    - "Kindle Wakes", undated (Box 46)
    - Lady Godiva, 1927 July, undated; 4 (Box 46)
    - Lady Godiva, 1928-1961, undated; 10 (Box 47)
    - Lady Godiva, 1928-1951, undated; 5 (Box 48)
    - "Land of Our Fathers", 1941-1942, undated; 3 (Box 48)
    - The Life of the Party, 1950 (Box 48)
    - The Life of the Party, 1950, undated; 3 (Box 49)
    - Love for Love, 1936 June 27, undated; 4 (Box 49)
    - "Lysistrata", [1948] (Box 50)
    - The Magic Curtain, undated; 6 (Box 50)
    - "A Man's Job", undated; 2 (Box 51)
    - Matinata, undated (Box 51)
    - The Merchant of Venice, undated (Box 51)
    - "A Modern Marriage", undated (Box 51)
    - "A Mood", 1922 (Box 51)
    - Moses, 1922-1924, undated; 5 (Box 51)
    - Moses, 1922-1924, undated; 7 (Box 52)
    - Moses, 1922 (Box 53)
    - "No More Patent Lawyers", 1934 February 5, undated; 5 (Box 53)
    - "On the Square", 1917, undated; 3 (Box 53)
    - "On the Square", 1917 (Box 54)
    - "The Pagan Princess", undated (Box 54)
    - "Patent Applied For", undated; 2 (Box 54)
    - "The Peacemaker", undated (Box 54)
    - "Petticoat Government", 1950-1962, undated; 13 (Box 55)
    - "Petticoat Government", 1950-1952; 2 (Box 56)
    - Pie, 1919 (Box 56)
    - The Play's the Thing, 1960 March 4, undated; 4 (Box 56)
    - The Play's the Thing, [1960], undated; 4 (Box 57)
    - The Play's the Thing, 1959, undated; 8 (Box 58)
    - The Play's the Thing, undated; 5 (Box 59)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness, undated; 3 (Box 59)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness, 1933-1946, undated; 7 (Box 60)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness, 1929-1959, undated; 7 (Box 61)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness, 1930-1933, undated; 7 (Box 62)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness, 1930-1933, undated; 9 (Box 63)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness, 1929-1933; 4 (Box 64)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness, 1946 April 25, undated; 7 (Box 65)
    - The Pyramid, 1920 (Box 65)
    - The Red Cloak, 1934 April 21 (Box 66)
    - "Revolt", undated (Box 66)
    - "Romance Play", undated (Box 66)
    - "Sailor's Delight", 1953 August 7, undated; 5 (Box 66)
    - "Sailor's Delight", 1953 July, undated; 2 (Box 67)
    - "The Scarlet Letter", undated (Box 67)
    - The School for Husbands, undated; 3 (Box 67)
      Variant title: "School for Lovers"
    - The School for Husbands, undated; 7 (Box 68)
    - The Sire de Maletroit's Door, undated (Box 68)
    - "Slackers", 1918 (Box 68)
    - "Slackers", 1918 (Box 69)
    - "Some Observations on the Act of Writing", undated (Box 69)
    - "Speed", undated (Box 69)
    - "The Starcross Story", 1953 (Box 69)
    - Suzanna and the Elders, 1936-1938, undated; 6 (Box 69)
      Variant titles: "Harmony Heights" and "Yankee Paradise"
    - Suzanna and the Elders, 1934-1938, undated; 10 (Box 70)
    - Suzanna and the Elders, 1937 July 1, undated; 4 (Box 71)
    - Tangerine, undated; 3 (Box 71)
      Variant title: "Love Ltd."
    - "There's No Place Like Home", undated (Box 71)
    - "These Modern Women", 1927-1928, undated; 4 (Box 72)
    - "The Thirteenth Apostle", 1923, undated; 4 (Box 72)
    - "This Marriage Revolt", 1926 (Box 72)
    - "This Marriage Revolt", 1926-1927, undated; 9 (Box 73)
    - "This Marriage Revolt", 1927 (Box 74)
    - "Too Good for God", undated (Box 74)
    - "Too Holy for Heaven", 1922 (Box 74)
    - "Too Holy for Heaven", 1922 (Box 74)
    - "Troubadours of God", undated (Box 74)
    - Turandot, Princess of China, undated; 3 (Box 74)
    - "Twice Shy", 1939-1952, undated; 5 (Box 74)
    - "Twice Shy", 1939-1952, undated; 7 (Box 75)
    - "Urial da Costa", undated (Box 75)
    - "White Shadows in the South Seas", undated; 2 (Box 75)
    - "Young People", 1922 (Box 75)
  - Correspondence and Subject Files, 1923-1959
    Material consists of correspondence, financial records, press clippings, notes, contracts, photographs, etc. related to Langner's writings or other subjects. Container numbers in square brackets reflect the numbers on the original boxes.
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject.
    - "Bride of Torozko" (produced at Wesport Country Playhouse) and Dream Child Corporation [container 114], 1934-1936; 4 (Box 76)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes [container 48], 1957-1959, undated; 4 (Box 77)
    - The Magic Curtain [container 125], 1952-1954; 5 (Box 78)
    - Moses and other works [container 130], 1924-1939; 10 (Box 79)
    - Notebooks ("Scenario books") containing scripts, notes and character studies for various plays including Suzanna and the Elders and "Heaven on Earth" [container 120], 1930-1946, undated; 3 (Box 80)
    - Eugene O'Neill, Carlotta O'Neill, "The Iceman Cometh," and other O'Neill plays [container 49], 1929-1949, undated; 7 (Box 81)
    - "[Once Married,] Twice Shy" [container 84], 1952-1953, undated (Box 82)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness [container 128], 1934-1950; 3 (Box 83)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness [container 132], 1933-1934, undated; 4 (Box 84)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness [container 134], 1933-1934; 2 (Box 85)
    - The School for Husbands [container 129], 1930-1935, undated; 8 (Box 86)
    - Suzanna and the Elders [container 117], 1940-1950, undated; 7 (Box 87)
    - Suzanna and the Elders [container 119], 1940, undated; 4 (Box 88)
    - Suzanna and the Elders and American Theatre Wing (Armina Marshall) [container 136], 1942-1946, undated; 3 (Box 89)
    - Theatre Guild Bulletin [container 138], 1923-1927 (Box 90)
    - Various plays, including Tangerine, Lady Godiva, Moses, Henry Behave, "Pyramid", These Modern Women, "Fledermaus", and Matinata [container 131], 1922-1946, undated; 12 (Box 91)
    - Theatre Guild and Theatre Guild Magazine [container 137], 1917-1956, undated; 7 (Box 92)
      Includes correspondence with or regarding Tennesse Williams, Morris Carnovsky, Vladimir Nemerovich-Danchenko, Edmund Wilson and others. Material was apparently gathered by Langer for future writing projects.
  - Oversize, 1922-1928
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, undated; 7 (Box 93 (Oversize))
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, 1922-1928, undated; 6 (Box 94 (Oversize))
    - Suzanna and the Elders [container 136], undated; 2 (Box 95 (Oversize))
- Material Formerly Part of the Eugene O'Neill Papers, 1913-1963; Series II; 0.42; (1 box)
  Consists of typescript iterations of plays by Eugene O'Neill, inscribed by O'Neill to Lawrence Langner.
  - Writings of Eugene O'Neill
    - Hughie, 1960 September 7 (Box 96)
    - A Moon for the Misbegotten, undated (Box 96)
    - Rocky, 1960-1963; 2 (Box 96)
    - Strange Interlude, 1960 June 17; 3 (Box 96)
    - Thirst, 1913 (Box 96)
    - A Touch of the Poet, 1960 September 7 (Box 96)
- Material Formerly Part of the Theatre Guild Archive, 1914-1983; Series III; 9.43; (22 boxes)
  Includes correspondence, subject files, and financial records related to the writing, production, and publication of Langner's writings; his work with the Theatre Guild; his law firm; and the National Inventor's Council, among other topics.
  Organized under six headings: Correspondence, Writings, Subject Files, Personal Papers, Printed Material, and Photographs.
  - Correspondence, 1914-1961
    Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
    - American Academy of Dramatic Arts, 1946 February-March (Box 97)
    - The American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee, Inc., 1957 December 23 (Box 97)
    - Anderson, H. N., 1914 July 28 (Box 97)
    - The Columbia University Student Council, 1955 (Box 97)
    - Curtis, Morris & Safford, 1957 (Box 97)
    - Dean, Basil, 1922 January 5 (Box 97)
    - Institute of Inventive Research, 1951 (Box 97)
    - Irving Trust, 1958 (Box 97)
    - Langner, Marilyn, 1957-1958 (Box 97)
    - Langner, Parry, Card & Langner, 1954-1960; 10 (Box 97)
    - Schneider, Victor, 1957-1958 (Box 97)
    - Theatre Arts Monthly, 1953 (Box 97)
    - Westport Broadcasting, 1958-1959 (Box 97)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 1927-1961; 11 (Box 97)
  - Writings, 1919-1983
    The majority of writings are arranged alphabetically by title, followed by writings arranged by genre.
    - "American Playwright", 1923 November 14 (Box 98)
    - "The American Theatre Forwards or Backwards", undated (Box 98)
    - "Are There Mental Appetites?", undated (Box 98)
    - "Back to the Box Office", 1929 February 9 (Box 98)
    - "The Bride of Torozko", undated (Box 98)
    - "Can Shakespeare Be Translated into English?", undated (Box 98)
    - Champagne, Sec, 1925-1959, undated; 2 (Box 98)
    - "Code of the Theatre", 1933 July 28 (Box 98)
    - "The Critic & the Playwright", 1934 February 21 (Box 98)
    - "Cuba Libra", 1959 (Box 98)
    - "The Death Watch", 1929 January 29 (Box 98)
    - Dr. Knock, 1950-1951 (Box 98)
    - "Down with Darwin", undated (Box 98)
    - "The Eleven Commandments", 1928 October 19 (Box 98)
    - The Famous Case of National Kink Safety Pin Co. vs. International Bump Co. et al, 1924; 2 (Box 98)
    - "Fancy Dress", undated (Box 98)
    - "Fear", undated (Box 98)
    - "The Fluctuating Theatre", 1954 (Box 98)
    - "Fruits of Culture", 1958 November 10 (Box 98)
    - G. B. S. and the Lunatic, 1963 November 23 (Box 98)
    - Graduation Address: American Academy of Dramatic Arts, 1931 March 6 (Box 98)
    - "Havana -- Or Two Dollars, 1933 January 26 (Box 98)
    - "Hit-Or-Miss Theatre", 1930 March 3 (Box 98)
    - Homer Fickett, 1953, undated (Box 98)
    - "How to Read a Play", 1954 (Box 98)
    - "Humane Use of the Atom Bomb", undated (Box 98)
    - "Hurrah! for Constructionism!", undated (Box 98)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, 1949-1958, undated; 26 (Box 98)
    - The Importance of Wearing Clothes, 1959, undated; 11 (Box 99)
    - "In Defense of Obscenity", undated (Box 99)
    - Israel Zangwill, 1926 August 3 (Box 99)
    - "The Jehlinger Method", undated (Box 99)
    - Lady Godiva, 1929-1952; 3 (Box 99)
    - The Life of the Party, 1950 (Box 99)
    - "The Little Theatre Grows Up", undated (Box 99)
    - The Magic Curtain, 1927-1958, undated; 21 (Box 99)
    - The Magic Curtain, 1983 July 6 (Box 100)
    - "Michael Arlen", undated (Box 100)
    - "Modjeska", undated (Box 100)
    - "Mr. Lee: An Appraisal and an Appreciation", 1953, undated (Box 100)
    - "A New Deal for the Theatre", undated (Box 100)
    - "A New Play", 1932 November 30 (Box 100)
    - "Of Playwrights", 1968 May 20, undated; 2 (Box 100)
    - Orchids & Salami, 1953 (Box 100)
    - Patent Applied For, 1918-1923; 2 (Box 100)
    - The Play's the Thing, 1963 February (Box 100)
    - "Problems", undated (Box 100)
    - "Proposal Regarding Jerusalem", undated (Box 100)
    - The Pursuit of Happiness, 1946-1960, undated; 9 (Box 100)
    - Suzanna and the Elders, 1940 (Box 100)
    - The Sire de Maletroit's Door, 1922-1951; 2 (Box 100)
    - "Some Comments Regarding the Theatre Guild", undated (Box 100)
    - The Story of the Theatre Guild: 1919-1947, 1937-1962, undated; 7 (Box 100)
    - "Memorandum Regarding Theatre Guild", undated (Box 100)
    - Theatre Guild Subscribers, 1923-1924 (Box 100)
    - "The Theatre in France", 1923 November 5 (Box 100)
    - "The Theatre Shows Its Teeth", 1933 October 4, undated (Box 100)
    - "The Thirteenth Apostle", 1923 (Box 100)
    - "This Marriage Revolt", 1927 (Box 100)
    - "Too True To Be Good", 1932 November 29 (Box 100)
    - "Try Out System", 1932 October 29 (Box 101)
    - "The Value of the Summer Theatres", 1933 March 21 (Box 101)
    - "Wanted: Rogues and Vagabonds", 1929 July 24 (Box 101)
    - "A Welcome to New Playwrights", undated (Box 101)
    - "What Every Girl Should Know About Patents", 1949 October 26, undated (Box 101)
    - "What's Right and Wrong With the Crazy American Theatre -- 1962-1963", 1962 December 12 (Box 101)
    - "What's the Matter With the Road?", 1929 August (Box 101)
    - "What Will the Talking Pictures Do to the Theatre?", 1928 July 23 (Box 101)
    - "Whither Repertory?", 1933 March 3 (Box 101)
    - Will Hays, 1928 March 14 (Box 101)
    - Articles, circa 1919-1955; 15 (Box 101)
    - Book contracts, 1932-35 (Box 101)
    - Indexes, undated (Box 101)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1940-1950, undated (Box 101)
    - Plays, 1934-1945, undated; 4 (Box 102)
    - Song-Poems, undated; 2 (Box 102)
    - Speeches, 1928-1942, undated; 2 (Box 102)
  - Subject Files, 1921-1959
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Biographies; Who's Who, 1947-1948 (Box 103)
    - Cherokee Constr[uction] Co[mpany] (empty folder), undated (Box 103)
    - Contributions, Subscriptions, Engagements, 1916-1925, undated (Box 103)
    - Copyright, 1922-1934 (Box 103)
    - Donations, 1956 (Box 103)
    - League of New York Theatres (empty folder), undated (Box 103)
    - The Magic Morning (empty folder), undated (Box 103)
    - Marcus Heiman, 1957 (Box 103)
    - Miscellaneous (empty folder), undated) (Box 103)
    - National Inventors Council, 1954-1957; 5 (Box 103)
    - National Inventors Council, 1941-1955; 3 (Box 104)
    - Playwriting Lectures, Westport Playhouse, 1957 (Box 104)
    - Rodgers Dorothy - Johnny Mop, 1950 (Box 104)
    - Royalties, 1965-1958; 2 (Box 104)
    - Stage Magazine (empty folder), undated (Box 104)
    - Versatiller, 1958-1959 (Box 104)
  - Personal Papers, 1915-1959
    Arranged by type of material.
    - Financial records, 1915-1957, undated; 7 (Box 105)
    - Medical records, undated (Box 105)
    - Will, 1959; 2 (Box 105)
    - Personal items, 1925-1951, undated (Box 105)
    - Jury Duty, 1957 (Box 105)
    - Label, undated (Box 105)
    - Books ordered for LL, 1957 (Box 105)
    - Scrapbooks, undated (Box 105)
  - Printed Material, 1948-1960
    - Printed material, undated; 5 (Box 106)
    - Printed material, circa 1948-1959; 10 (Box 107)
    - Clippings, circa 1949-1958; 2 (Box 107)
    - Clippings, 1960s; 3 (Box 108)
  - Photographs, 1960-1963
    Photographs are unsorted.
    - Unsorted photographs, 1960-1963, undated; 6 (Box 109)
    - Photo album, undated
  - Oversize, 1934